Guide to the Ethelbert Nevin Collection, 1834-1980 CAM.NEV.1987.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Correspondence, 1880-1939; 1880-1901; VI.
  - Letters sent to and from Ethelbert Nevin, 1.
    - Mother Nevin, letters sent to, B.
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, September 12, 1891 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 462)
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, September 19, 1891 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 463)
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, October 6, 1891 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 464)
        138 Air Malakoff. ALS.
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, October 18, 1891 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 465)
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, December 21, 1891 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 466)
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, May 2, 1892 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 467)
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, May 30, 1892 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 468)
        Kurfusten Damm. ALS, TL.
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, June 12, 1892 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 469)
        Friedrich str. 49a, Berlin. ALS, TL.
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, November 11, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 470)
        Boston, 44 Mt. Vernon St. ALS, TL.
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, November 24, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 471)
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, November 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 472)
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, May 4, 1895 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 473)
        Firenze. ALS, TL.
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, June 4, 1895 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 474)
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, August 4, 1895 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 475)
        Montepiano. ALS.
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, September 24, 1895 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 476)
        Florence. ALS.
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, November 25, 1895 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 477)
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, January 8, 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 478)
        Florence. ALS, TL.
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, January 27, 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 479)
        Firenze. TL.
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, March 8, 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 480)
        Florence. TL.
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, May 17, 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 481)
        Venice. TL.
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, December 4, 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 482)
        Paris, 42 rue Galilée. ALS, TL.
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, January 18, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 483)
        New Haven, Connecticut. ALS, TL.
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 484)
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, Jan. 23, 1887 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 485)
        Unspecified. TL: First line: "Your most welcome letter came this morning…" In clippings extract folder.
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, January 19, 1886 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 486)
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, December 4, 1888 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 487)
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, January 25, 1886 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 488)
        ALS. Eight pages.
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, October 1889 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 489)
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, March 13, 1888 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 490)
        ALS and TLS
      - Elizabeth (Mother) Nevin, January 8, 1888 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 491)
        ALS and TLS. 7 Park Street.
    - Group of letters to parents, 1885; C.
      Contents are loosely organized across three folders containing extracts from letters unless mentioned otherwise.
      - MISSING Father, January 3, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 492)
      - Mother (extract), January 16, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 493)
        Found with loose letter clippings in one folder.
      - Mother, March 5, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 494)
      - Mother, March 15, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 495)
      - Mother, March 22, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 496)
      - Mother, April 21, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 497)
      - Mother (Extract), May 24, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 498)
      - Mother, June 7, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 499)
      - Mother, October 14, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 500)
      - Mother, October 28, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 501)
      - Mother, November 2, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 502)
        Found in folder # 121.
      - Mother (extract), November 9, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 503)
      - Mother, November 23, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 504)
      - Mother, December 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 505)
      - MISSINGMother (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 506)
    - Letters sent to Anne Paul Nevin (A.P.N., i.e. the wife of Ethelbert Nevin), 1883-1901; D.
      - Anne, 1883 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 507)
        Music Room. 6th St. Pittsburgh. ALS, TL.
      - Anne, November 8, 1892 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 508)
        (Birthday Note) Berlin. ALS, TL.
      - Anne, November 26, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 509)
        Albemarle Hotel, Madison Square, New York. ALS, TL.
      - Anne, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 510)
      - Anne, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 511)
        Boston, 40 Mt. Vernon St. ALS, TL.
      - Anne, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 512)
        Sunday, 1893. ALS, TL.
      - MISSING Anne, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 513)
        Unspecified address. ALS, TL (2 copies).
      - Anne, February 1, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 514)
        "Fulda" (steamship). ALS: Written on "Norddeutscher Lloyd Bremen Dampfer "Fulda" stationary, TL.
      - MISSING Anne, February 1, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 515)
        "Fulda" (steamship). ALS: Written on "Norddeutscher Lloyd Bremen Dampfer "Fulda" stationary. Missing.
      - Anne, February 8, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 516)
        Algiers. ALS, TL.
      - Anne, February 9, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 517)
        Hotel Kirsch, Mustapha. ALS, TL.
      - Anne, February 15, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 518)
        Mustapha. ALS, TL.
      - Anne, February 17, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 519)
      - Anne, February 21, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 520)
      - Anne, February 26, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 521)
        Mustapha. ALS,TL.
      - Anne, March 2, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 522)
        Morley's Hotel, Trafalgar Square, London W.C. ALS, TL.
      - Anne, April 1, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 523)
        Unspecified address. ALS, TL.
      - Anne, December 4, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 524)
        Gilsey House, NY. TL: Fragment.
      - Anne, November 14, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 525)
        "Iroquois." ALS, TL.
      - Anne, November 17, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 526)
        Gilsey House, NY. ALS, TL (2 copies).
      - Anne, December 5, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 527)
        Gilsey House, NY. ALS,TL.
      - MISSING Anne, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 528)
        Algiers. ALS,TL. Folder # 55.
      - MISSING Anne, 1894; 23. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 529)
      - MISSING Anne, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 530)
        Gilsey House, NY. ALS,TL. Folder # 55.
      - MISSING Anne, January 12, 1895; 25. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 531)
        The Shoreham, Washington D.C.
      - Anne, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 532)
      - Anne, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 533)
      - Anne, February 12, 1895 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 534)
        Rathbun House, Elmira, NY. ALS,TL.
      - Anne, February 13, 1895 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 535)
        Gilsey House, NY. ALS,TL (2 copies).
      - Anne, February 15, 1895 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 536)
      - Anne, March 2, 1895 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 537)
      - Anne, April 24, 1897 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 538)
        April 1897 Thursday 11:30 AM. Unspecified address. ALS.
      - Anne, April 21, 1897 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 539)
        Paris. ALS, TL (two copies). Not mentioned in Word doc.
      - Anne, 1897 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 540)
        Paris. ALS,TL (2 copies).
      - Anne, August 2, 1897 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 541)
        Unspecified address. ALS,TL (2 copies).
      - Anne, August 11, 1897 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 542)
        Unspecified address. ALS,TL.
      - Anne, October 1898 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 543)
      - Anne, 1897 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 544)
        Unknown Month 20, 1897. Unspecified address. ALS,TL (2 copies).
      - Anne, 1897 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 545)
        Saturday, 17th, 1897. Unspecified address. ALS,TL.
      - Anne, 1897 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 546)
      - Anne, 1897 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 547)
        42 Rue Galilee "Good Friday" Paris. ALS,TL.
      - Anne, 1898 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 548)
        The St. Botolph Club, 2 Newbury St., Boston. ALS,TL. Fragment also available.
      - Anne, July 24, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 549)
        Unspecified. ALS,TL.
      - Anne, December 17, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 550)
      - Anne, January 10, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 551)
        Albemarle Hotel, Madison Square, West, New York. ALS,TL.
      - Anne, April 10, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 552)
      - Anne, September 27, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 553)
        St. Matthew's Military School, Dobbs Ferry-on-Hudson. ALS,TL.
      - Anne, October 1, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 554)
      - Anne, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 555)
        Hotel Riverside, Cambridge Springs, PA. ALS,TL.
      - Anne, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 556)
        Hotel Riverside, Cambridge Springs, PA. ALS.
      - MISSING Anne, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 557)
        Hotel Riverside, Cambridge Springs, PA. ALS,TL. Missing
      - Anne, 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 558)
        half a piece of stationary labeled "Berlin, 1885."
      - Anne, February 13, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 559)
        New Haven, Connecticut. ALS,TL.
      - Anne (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 560)
      - Anne (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 561)
        Saturday, 12:30 AM, ALS, TL: First line: "You can have no idea how much we miss you."
      - Anne, 57. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 562)
        Unspecified. ALS, TL: First line: "I thought perhaps you would like to keep this book…"
      - Anne (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 563)
        Unspecified. ALS, TL: First line: "I know you are dead tired…"
      - Anne (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 564)
        Unspecified. ALS, TL: First line: "This time yesterday we were together…"
      - Anne, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 565)
        Saturday, 1893 44 Mt. Vernon St. No. 1 TLS. two copies.
      - Anne, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 566)
      - Anne, January 12, 1895 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 567)
        The Shoreham, Washington DC. ALS & TLS.
      - Anne, February 7, 1895 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 568)
        Gilsey House. ALS, TL (two copies).
      - Anne, Good Friday 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 569)
      - Anne (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 570)
        ALS and TLS "Bert's Proposal."
      - Anne, Feb. 6, 1895 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 571)
        TLS and ALS
    - Letters from EWN to other family members, 1887-1901; E.
      - Nevin, Doris (Daughter), August 12, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 572)
        Engleside, Beach Haven, NJ. ALS, TL: written on Engleside Beach Haven stationary.
      - Nevin, Ethelbert Paul (son), October 8, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 573)
      - Nevin, Ethelbert Paul (son), November 27, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 574)
        Vineacre. ALS, TL.
      - Nevin, Ethelbert Paul (son), December 5, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 575)
        Unspecified, ALS, TL.
      - MISSING Nevin, Ethelbert Paul (son), October 21, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 576)
        40 Trumbace St. New Haven, Connecticut. ALS. Missing.
      - Nevin, Ethelbert Paul (son), February 18, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 577)
        Unspecified. ALS, TL. Original Autograph typewritten.
      - Nevin, Ethelbert Paul (son), March 3, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 578)
        Vineacre, Sewickley. ALS, TL. Original Autograph typewritten. (Date sic 1990).
      - Nevin, Ethelbert Paul (son), June 4, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 579)
        Vineacre, Sewickley. TL
      - Nevin, Ethelbert Paul (son), May 15, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 580)
        Vineacre, Sewickley. ALS, TL.
      - Nevin, Ethelbert Paul (son), May 28, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 581)
      - Nevin, Ethelbert Paul (son), October 21, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 582)
        40 Trumbace St. New Haven, Connecticut. TL.
      - Nevin, Ethelbert Paul (son), February 12, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 583)
      - MISSING Nevin, Ethelbert Paul (son), June 4, unknown year (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 584)
      - Nevin, Robert (Bob), February 16, 1887 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 585)
      - Nevin, Robert (Bob), February 28, 1888 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 586)
    - Letters from EWN to others, 1893-1900; F.
      - B. Schotts Sohne, August 21, 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 587)
        Fontainebleau. ALS, TL.
      - MISSISNG B Schotts Sohne, July 20, 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 588)
        Fontainebleau. ALS.
      - MISSING B. Schotts Sohne, October 20, 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 589)
      - [Bakewell], Charlie, April 1, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 590)
      - MISSING Boardman, Mrs. William D, October 7, 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 591)
        Paris, 42 rue Galilée. ALS.
      - Boardman, Mrs. William D, October 26,1895 [1896] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 592)
        Paris, 42 rue Galilée. ALS: Original date on letter is erroneous. Postmark on envelope is 1896.
      - Boardman, Mrs. William D., 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 593)
      - Boardman, Mrs. William D, November 14, 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 594)
        Paris, 38 rue Galilée. ALS, TL.
      - Boardman, Mrs. William D, March 17, 1897 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 595)
        42 rue Galilée. ALS, TL.
      - Boardman, Mrs. William D., September 10, 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 596)
      - "Mizpah", September 29, 1898 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 597)
        Unspecified. ALS, TL. Folder # 18.
      - Rogers, Mr, May 17, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 598)
      - Schirmer, Gustave, August 26, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 599)
        Manchester By the Sea. TL, with notations penciled in.
      - Schirmer, Gustave, November 29, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 600)
        Sewickley. TL.
      - Schirmer, Gustave, October 4, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 601)
        Sewickley, PA. TL, edits in pencil.
      - Schirmer, Gustave, July 12, 1895 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 602)
        Montepiano, Italy. TL.
      - White, Mrs., April 6, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 603)
        Sewickley. ALS, TL.
      - Schirmer, Gustave, October 19, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 604)
        TL with pencil corrections. Sewickley PA
    - Daniel Gregory Mason Letters, 1891-1892; G.
      Group of letters from EWN transcribed by Mason for publication and includes explanatory commentary on Colony Club stationary. Includes a short anecdote concerning "Narcissus" by Mason. All four letters are in one folder.
      - Mason, Daniel Gregory, May 12, 1891 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 605)
        30 Pinckney St. Boston. TL.
      - Mason, Daniel Gregory, April 12, 1892 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 606)
        Paris. TL.
      - Mason, Daniel Gregory, May 23, 1892 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 607)
        Kurfursten Damm Berlin. TL.
      - Mason, Daniel Gregory, August 12, 1892 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 608)
    - Letters from Ethelbert Nevin to Gustave Schirmer in which dates are dubious, 1895-1899; H. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 609)
      All letters are typed extracts typed into one continuous document.
      - Gustave Schirmer, January 2, 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item a)
        Firenze [Italy]. TL.
      - Gustave Schirmer, May 21, 1895 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item b)
      - Gustave Schirmer, July 10 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item c)
        Montepiano, Tuscan Apennines. TL.
      - Gustave Schirmer, September 20, 1895 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item d)
      - Gustave Schirmer, June 28, 1898 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item e)
      - Gustave Schirmer, January 17, 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item f)
        Firenze. TL. Extract.
      - Gustave Schirmer, November 19, 1895 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item g)
      - Gustave Schirmer, September 14, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item h)
      - Gustave Schirmer, 1895-1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item i)
    - Unidentified and Fragments, I.
      Fragments are located in one folder.
      - Unknown Parent (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 610)
        Boston. TL: Complete Letter. Concerns the death of President Garfield. The date on the letter 09/30/1881 is struck.
      - Unknown (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 611)
        Address not specified. TL: Complete letter. Postscript concerning drawing lessons. Missing.
      - Unknown Parent (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 613)
        7 Park St. ALS, TL. Missing.
      - Unknown (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 614)
        Unspecified. TL: Fragment. First line "(incoherent, see letter) Mr. Lang's sister in law, etc...," all penciled out, A penciled '15' appears at top. Missing.
      - Unknown Parent (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 615)
        Unspecified. TL: Fragment. First line: "...gave me an exercise..." A penciled "22" appears at top. Missing.
      - Unknown Parent (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 616)
        Unspecified. TL: Fragment. First line (closing) "Love to all. Your affectionate son, Bert." Typed page number "14." Appears with partial letter to Father (11/27/1881). Extract.
      - Unknown (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 617)
        TL: Fragment. First line. "... a ticket for the symphony concert." Appears with complete letter to father (09/17/1881). Penciled "9" appears at top. Missing.
      - Unknown (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 618)
        Unspecified. TL: Fragment. First line: "It was gotten up beautifully..." Missing.
    - Letters from Family to EWN, 1888-1898; J.
      - Mother, December 9, 1988 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 619)
        Vineacre. ALS.
      - Mother, November 23, 1890 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 620)
      - Mother, March 20, 1892 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 621)
      - Mother, March 29, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 622)
        Vineacre, ALS.
      - Mother, October 14, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 623)
        Viineacre. ALS.
      - Mother, November 11, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 624)
      - Mother, February 13, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 625)
      - Paul, J.W. (Father-in-law), February 27, 1898 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 626)
        Grasmere, FL. ALS.
    - Letters from others to EWN, K.
      - Adams, Juliette G, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 627)
        Chicago. ALS.
      - Abbott, Lyman, October 2, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 628)
        Brooklyn, NY. ALS.
      - Anonymous [?] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 629)
        Unspecified location. ALS.
      - Baldwin, W.W, May 30, 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 630)
      - Boise, Annie V, December 5, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 631)
        Kurfürsten str. 100. ALS.
      - Cather, Willa B, February 28, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 632)
        ALS
      - von Finck, Clothilde, January 25, 1891 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 633)
      - Hermas, George F, 07/18/1892 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 634)
        10 Bernard Crescent, Edinburgh, Scotland. ALS.
      - Rawle, Francis W, et al, May 14, 1891 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 635)
        Exeter, New Hampshire. ALS: From four students at Exeter: Francis W. Rawle, W. Powell Robins, W. Edward Butler, and A.W. [Clooke].
      - Schirmer, Gustave, September 8, 1892 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 636)
        New York, ALS.
      - Tapper, Thomas, February 5, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 637)
      - Ward, Lydia Avery, July 24, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 638)
        Chicago. ALS: Typed note.
      - Windeler, Laura, June 9, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 639)
        Stockbridge. ALS, TL.
    - Letters from Anne Paul Nevin to EWN, 1894; L.
      - EWN, February 7, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 640)
      - EWN, February 18, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 641)
  - Letters between the Nevins and the Dicksons, 1883-1900; 2.
    - Anne Paul Nevin to Elizabeth Dickson, November 7, 1897; A. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 642)
      [Sent from] 221 W. 57th St. [To] Lizzie (Elizabeth) Dickson. ALS.
    - Ethelbert Nevin to Tom Dickson, April 26, 1890 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 643)
      [Sent from]160 Mt. Vernon St. [To] Tom Dickson. ALS. Folder # 11.
    - Ethelbert Nevin to Tom Dickson, June 9, 1892 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 644)
      [Sent from] Berlin, Friedrich str. 49a. [To] Tom Dickson. ALS.
    - Ethelbert Nevin to Elizabeth Dickson, November 6, 1883 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 645)
      [Sent from] 36 Sixth St. [to] Lizzie (Elizabeth) Dickson. ALS: Sends regrets for a party.
    - Ethelbert Nevin to Elizabeth Dickson, July 31, 1883 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 646)
      [Sent from] Hades [to] Lizzie (Elizabeth Dickson). ALS: invitation to a concert.
    - Ethelbert Nevin to Elizabeth Dickson, July 27, 1884 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 647)
      [Sent from] Vineacre [to] Lizzie (Elizabeth Dickson). ALS.
    - Ethelbert Nevin to Tom Dickson, January 5, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 648)
      [Sent from] Vineacre [to] Tom Dickson. ALS: Brief note includes a small poem.
    - Ethelbert Nevin to Elizabeth Nevin (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 649)
      [Sent from] Edgeworth. [To] Lizzie (Elizabeth) and Clara Dickson. ALS: Brief note, concerns a tennis match.
    - Ethelbert Nevin to Elizabeth Dickson (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 650)
      [Sent from] Vineacre [to] Lizzie (Elizabeth) Dickson. ALS: Brief note, sends regrets. Original envelope included.
    - Robert Paul Nevin, Jr., to Elizabeth Dickson, January 20, 1891 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 651)
      [Sent from] Vineacre [to] Elizabeth Dickson. ALS.
    - Robert Paul Nevin, Jr., to Elizabeth Dickson, January 21, 1892 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 652)
      [Sent from] Diamond Alley [to] Elizabeth Dickson. (Postmarked on aforementioned date). ALS.
  - Letters from family members to Anne Paul Nevin, 1898; 3.
    - Nevin, Robert P, March 28, 1898 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 653)
  - Letters from APN to Others, 1899-1939; 4.
    - Schirmer, Gustave, March 22, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 654)
      Sewickley, PA. ALS.
    - Schirmer, Gustave (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 655)